《超感警探》前情提要
Previously on "The Mentalist"...
十年前  被称作血腥约翰的连环杀手
Ten years ago, the serial killer known as Red John
杀害了我的妻子和女儿
killed my wife and daughter.
自那以后我们一直在追捕他
We've been hunting for him ever since.
我们自称为"布莱克组织"
We call ourselves the Blake Association.
组织里还有些什么人
Well, who else is in the association?
警察  法官  联调局探员
Cops, judges, F.B.I. agents.
任何一个有秘密需要掩盖的执法人员
Anyone in law enforcement that needs a secret covered up.
一个腐败警察的秘密组织
A secret society of dirty cops.
血腥约翰是成员之一
And Red John's a member.
基拉·汀斯利死之前跟我说了件事
Kira Tinsley told me something before she passed.
她告诉我杀她的人  也就是血腥约翰
She told me that her killer-- Red John--
有个纹身
has a tattoo--
左臂上有三个点
Three dots on his left arm.
到底谁是血腥约翰
So who's Red John?
今天我们很高兴地宣布
Today we're pleased to announce
我们终于确认了他的身份与面目
that we--we finally have a name, a face.
执法部门负责人
The director of the division of law enforcement,
盖尔·伯特仑局长  就是血腥约翰
Gail Bertram, is Red John.
我手里有一份
I am holding in my hand a writ
联邦法官签署的令状
from a federal judge.
联调局将立即关闭你们部门
The F.B.I.'s closing down your organization right now.
结束了  这里没我们的事儿了
We're done. There's nothing more to do here.
你不会放弃  我不信你会放弃
You're not quitting. I don't believe it.
目前的情况我们已经无法掌控了
It's out of our hands for now.
保持联络  好吗
I'll be in touch. Okay?
所有的一切  我很抱歉
I'm sorry. For everything.
里斯本
Lisbon.
很高兴你能过来
Glad you can join us.
路上塞车
Traffic.
简在哪
Hmm. Where's Jane?
他一有空就过来见你
He'll be in to see you as soon as he's able.
这边走
This way.
请坐下
Please, take a seat.
情况真是一团糟  对吧
Boy, this is a mess, huh?
糟透了
A big mess.
-听着  我觉得我们...  -一会儿有你说的机会
- Look, I think we all-- - You can talk later.
我能理解
Now I understand...
你们现在肯定都很害怕
You must all feel scared,
很紧张
nervous.
不知道接下来会发生什么事  对吗
Don't know what in the hell is gonna happen next, right?
-探员  -所以我来说明下接下来会发生的事
- Agent-- - So let me explain what's next.
接下来的几天
Over the next few days,
我们会找你们每个人谈话
we will be talking to each of you...
单独谈话
Individually.
你们有权委托律师或工会代表随行
You are entitled to bring along an attorney or a union rep,
由你们自己选择
should you so choose.
我们为何需要律师
Why would we need an attorney?
从我们的角度来看看这事  金宝
Well, let's look at this from our perspective, Kimball.
你们的上司伯特仑是个罪犯
Your boss Bertram is a criminal.
所以有可能你们也是
Makes sense that you might be one, too.
我们会非常仔细地审视你们每个人
We will be looking very closely at all of you.
如果你们有任何
If you have ever done anything
只要一点点可疑的举动
even remotely questionable,
我们都会发现
We will find out,
然后起诉你们
and we will prosecute.
当然了  除非
Unless, of course,
你们能够配合  那我们会非常非常满意
We feel very, very comfortable with your cooperation.
那样你们就有点回旋的余地
Then you got a little wiggle room.
加州  萨克拉门托  富兰克林区
联调局展开一场全球缉凶行动
The F.B.I. is overseeing an international manhunt
通缉著名的萨克拉门托执法部门官员
for prominent Sacramento law enforcement official
盖尔·伯特仑
Gail Bertram.
联调局方面证实
F.B.I. sources confirm
据信伯特仑就是臭名昭著的连环杀手血腥约翰
that Bertram is believed to be the notorious serial killer Red John,
他因在整个加利福尼亚州中心地带
Wanted for a string of grisly murders
犯下一系列恐怖凶案而被通缉
across the California heartland.
伙计
Hey, man.
你好吗
How's it going?
你这有公用电话吗
Do you have a pay phone?
在那边
It's right back there.
谢谢
Thank you.
阿里  你好啊  给我张六合彩
Hey, Ali, how you doing? Uh, give me a Pick 6...
再来一根菠萝味雪茄
And one of those pineapple cheroots.
六合彩  雪茄
Pick 6. Cheroot.
喂
Hello?
你好  派翠克
Hello, Patrick.
我用不着捏着嗓子讲话  对吧
I don't have to use a funny voice, do I?
你知道我是谁
You know who this is.
对  知道
Yes, I do.
感觉真奇怪啊  对吧
It's weird, huh?
因为我们上次...
'cause the last time we--
举起手来
Put your hands up--
喂
Hello?
还在吗
谢谢
Thanks.
别客气
No problem.
喂  伯特仑  还在听吗
Hello? Bertram? Hello?
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：灰灰是菇凉  王小麦  静静的木头 Michael  那时花开
超感警探
第六季
第八集
■
时间轴：Sgelibra  芝麻圆子  兜兜兜爹   校对：灰灰是菇凉
第六季
第八集
■
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   精校&总监：灰灰是菇凉
没人  长官
Clear, sir.
的确啊
No kidding.
他在哪
Where is he?
如果你问的是简  那我不知道
If you're asking about Jane, I don't know.
你去楼上找过了吗
Did you check upstairs?
找了
Yeah.
你也许还没听说
You know, maybe you haven't heard.
大约一小时前  盖尔·伯特仑
About an hour ago, Gail Bertram
在萨城东区的一个加油站杀了一个警察
killed a cop at a gas station in East Sac.
我听说了
I heard.
那你听说了伯特仑当时在加油站做什么吗
Did you hear what Bertram was doing at the gas station?
没
No.
他在打公用电话
Using a pay phone.
猜猜他打给了谁
Guess who he was calling.
我猜是简
I'm gonna guess Jane.
没错  那他在哪
Ahh. Yeah. So where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
我认为你清楚得很
I think you do.
我没法左右你的想法
I can't help what you think.
我认为你的男朋友和一名危险的逃犯勾结
I think your boyfriend is colluding with a dangerous fugitive.
我认为他已经深陷布莱克组织中无法自拔
I think he is up to his neck in this Blake Association craziness,
可能你也是
and probably you are, too.
我不是  他也不是
I'm not. He's not.
简无法阻止打给他的人
Jane can't help who calls him,
而且他也不是我的男朋友
and he's not my boyfriend.
真是太遗憾了  特蕾莎
It's a damn shame, Teresa.
人人都说
By all accounts...
你曾是个好警察
You were a good cop.
我现在依旧是
I still am.
头儿
Hey, boss!
瑞斯比
Rigsby?
周围安全吗
Is it safe?
嗯  你们在干嘛
Yeah. What are you doing?
我们听说了伯特仑今早干的事
We heard about what Bertram did this morning.
听说联调局的人在找我们
We heard the F.B.I. were looking for us.
所以现在是怎样  你们就躲在停车场吗
So what now? You're hiding in the parking lot?
不  我们不是躲起来  只是
No. No, we're not hiding. We're just...
低调行事
laying low.
我们暂时还安全
Well, we're safe for now.
至少现在还没有下达对我们的逮捕令
There's no arrest warrant that's put out for us just yet.
他们迟早会的
Give 'em time.
简在哪
Where's Jane?
别问
Don't ask.
她刚已经问了
She just did.
听我说
Listen to me.
如今加调局已经不复存在了
The C.B.I. is gone now.
我们只能靠自己了  你们得保护好自己
We're on our own. You need to protect yourselves.
你们不知道简在哪里  他在干什么
You don't know where Jane is, you don't know what he's doing,
也不想知道  明白了吗
and you don't want to know, you understand?
明白  头儿
Yes, boss.
-明白  头儿  -明白  头儿
- Yes, boss. - Yes, boss.
那就好
All right then.
但我已经不是你们的头儿了  关键就在这里
But I am not your boss anymore. That's the point.
我们只能靠自己
We're on our own.
我们明白的
Yeah, we get it.
那他在哪
So where is he?
加州  萨克拉门托  威廉兰德公园
你被通缉了
You're a wanted man.
我想也是
Well, I like to think so.
我说真的  艾伯特给你下了逮捕令
Seriously. Abbott put an actual warrant out on you.
也不是第一次了
Eh. It's not the first time.
所以你到底要不要告诉我
So you gonna tell me, or what?
哦对  伯特仑打给我了
Oh, yeah. Uh... Bertram called me.
我知道
I know.
他说了些什么
What did he say?
不管他想说什么  他那时都没来得及
Well, whatever he wanted to say, he didn't have time.
为什么他还在城里
Why the hell is he still here?
他想做什么
What does he want?
我猜他会很快再打来告诉我
I'm guessing he'll call back soon and tell me.
你的手机不安全  联调局...
Your phone's not safe. The F.B.I.--
对  他们装了窃听
Yeah, they have a tap on the line.
但他们还没追踪到
But they don't have a trace yet.
如果他们追踪到了  我现在就早该被捕了
If they had a trace, then I'd be arrested already.
也许如此  但他们早晚会追踪到你的
Maybe so, but sooner or later, they'll get a trace on you.
我知道
I know.
但在伯特仑打来之前我不能扔掉手机
But I can't get rid of my phone until Bertram calls.
所以事情就悬在这了
It's all very suspenseful.
他到底想干什么
What does he want?
谁
Who?
伯特仑
Bertram.
到时候就知道了
We'll see.
你在闪烁其词
Now you're being evasive.
小鸟的眼睛圆又亮
What beady little eyes birds have.
《小恐龙》[系列童书]  你知道吧
Tiny Dinosaurs, you know?
我知道
I know.
我知道你很清楚他的意图
I know you know what he wants.
他到底想干什么
What does he want?
-喂  -很抱歉我那时不得不挂电话
- Hello? - Oh, sorry I had to hang up on you.
今天实在太忙了
It's been a busy day.
没关系  这个电话不安全
Yeah, no problem. You know, this phone is not safe.
我马上再打给你
Let me call you back in a moment.
好的
Yeah.
他说什么
What'd he say?
稍等一下
Just a second.
你好啊
Hey. How you doing?
我出一百块换你的手机  行吗
I'll give you $100 for that phone.
什么
Huh?
两百块换你的手机
$200 for that phone.
这是什么骗局吗
What's the catch?
不是骗局
No catch.
三百块  外加
$300 plus...
一部替代机
a replacement phone.
那好吧
Uh, okay.
哥们  我一会儿再打给你
Yeah, dude, I'll call you right back.
交易愉快
Pleasure doing business with you.
谢了  伙计
Thanks, man.
他刚才到底说了什么
What did he say?
我觉得我们应该见面好好谈谈
Look, I think we should meet and talk.
-就我们俩  -就像约会一样吗
- Just the two of us. - What, like a date?
是啊
Yes...
不
No.
听着  游戏结束了
Look, the game is over.
我得说你我确实不分伯仲
I'd call it a very honorable tie.
既然现在一切都结束了
And now that it's over,
我真的觉得我们应该好好谈谈
I really think that we should talk.
停战  不带武器  不玩花招
You know, a truce. No weapons, no tricks.
就谈谈
Just talk.
然后各行其道
Then we both walk away.
谈谈  谈什么
Talk. About what?
谈谈这一切
Well... everything.
我想我们都需要有个了结  不是吗
I think we both could use a little closure, don't you?
就在今天  现在
It has to be today. You know, now.
我时间有点紧
I'm kind of pressed for time.
我怎么知道能否相信你呢
How do I know I can trust you?
都到现在了就别胆小了  派翠克
Ah, don't be timid now, Patrick.
我有那么多机会杀你  却都没下手  不是吗
I could have killed you many times, and I haven't, have I?
好吧  时间  地点
Okay. When and where?
非常好
Excellent.
半小时后弗里蒙特公园的喷泉边见
I'll be at the Fremont Park fountain in half an hour.
不行  我不知道那个地方  中央汽车站见
No. Don't know it. Central bus station.
-北入口  -不行  那里人太多
- North entrance. - Nah, There's too many people.
而且警察太多
There's too many cops.
你知道亚历山大公墓吗
You know Alexandria Cemetery?
我当然知道
Of course I do.
西门那边有个小教堂
Yeah, there's a chapel by the western gate.
行啊  半小时之后见
That--that'll do. Half an hour.
别迟到  我不能待太久
Don't be late. I can't wait around.
半小时之后见
Half an hour.
他说什么
What'd he say?
他想见我
He wants to meet with me.
这是个陷阱
It's a trap.
可能吧
Probably.
你准备怎么办
Well, what are you gonna do?
我去见他
I'm gonna meet him.
不行
You can't.
相信我  我知道自己在干什么
Trust me, I know what I'm doing.
简  别去  你想想
Jane, don't do this. Think about it.
联调局马上就要抓到伯特仑了
The F.B.I. is gonna get Bertram soon enough.
我不想他落在联调局手上
I don't want the F.B.I. to get him.
你知道这一天早晚会来
You knew this day was coming.
就是今天了
It's here.
那我和你一起去
Let me come with you.
不行  我不想让你牵扯进来
No, I don't want you involved.
牵扯  我早就深陷其中了
Involved? I am involved.
不能再这样了
Not anymore.
我要借你的枪
I'm gonna need to borrow your gun.
我的枪
My gun?
是  你的枪  我不会开枪的
Yes, your gun. I'm not gonna use it.
就是壮壮胆
Just a prop.
特蕾莎  请你相信我
Teresa, trust me, please.
相信我就好
Just trust me.
谢谢
Thank you.
那边吧
Like that way.
谢了
Thanks.
疑犯逃跑
The suspect got moved.
负责人呢  艾伯特在哪儿
Where's the man in charge here? Where is Abbott?
跪下
Get down on your knees.
把手举到我能看见的地方
Keep your hands where I can see them.
艾伯特在哪儿  我必须得走了
Where is Abbott? I-I have to go.
好了  淡定点  伙计们
All right, take it down a notch, people.
他又不是阿尔·卡彭
He's not Al Capone.
著名黑帮老大
艾伯特  请听我说
Abbott, please listen to me.
我看得出来你是个正人君子
I can tell that you're a man of honor.
我以我的名誉发誓  我一小时之后就回去自首
On my honor, I will give myself up in an hour.
但是现在  我...  我要
But right now I just-- I just need...
只要
Just...
算了
Forget it.
别别别  告诉我
No. No, no, no, no. No, tell me.
起来
Come on.
你要干什么  你需要什么
No, what do you need? What do you need, huh?
你需要一小时
You need an hour?
干什么
For what?
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
去见谁
Who are you gonna go meet?
不说吗
No?
那回局里说怎么样
Well, let's take a trip downtown, shall we?
没事  让她过来吧
No. You can let her go.
你好  里斯本女士
Hi, Miss Lisbon.
就算是咱们两个警察间帮个忙  艾伯特
Do me this one favor, Abbott, cop to cop.
放他走  我发誓到时候一定把他带回来
Let him go, and I swear I will bring him back later.
不可能
Not happening.
你们到底有什么紧急的事
And what is all this urgency I'm hearing here?
你们是跟伯特仑有约吧
You made a plan with Bertram.
是吗  是这样吗
Is that it? Is that what you did?
拜托了  艾伯特
Please, Abbott.
联调局  退后
FBI! Back it off!
-加调局  你给我退后  -怎么回事
- CBI. Back it up yourself. - What's this?
放他走  艾伯特  他什么也没做错
Let him go, Abbott. He's done nothing wrong.
好啊  各位
Hey, guys.
很高兴见到你们
You know, I-it's good to see you.
我本来不想打击你们的  但加调局已经不存在了
I hate to bring you down, but there is no CBI.
你们的警徽就是个玩具
That badge is a toy,
而你们只是在假扮警察
and you're all impersonating officers of the law.
随你怎么说  放他走
Whatever. Let him go.
你是缠上我了是吗
Are you mad-dogging me right now?
缠上联调局了
The F.B.I.?
你说你是真的联调局探员  有什么证据
You say you're legit F.B.I., but how do we know?
对  你们也许是布莱克组织的成员
Yeah, you could be members of the Blake Association
也不是没可能
for all we know.
我们不是
We're not.
拿出证明来
Prove it.
你的手下里德·史密斯就是其中之一
Your man Reede Smith was a member.
你为什么不可能是
Why not you?
而且我们怎么知道简会不会有危险
And how do we know Jane's not in danger?
太荒唐了
That's absurd.
抱歉 艾伯特探员
I'm sorry, Agent Abbott,
但是在确保他的安全之前
but it is our duty to protect this man
保护好他是我们的责任
until we're assured his safety.
放他走
Let him go.
别这样  别这样
No, no, no, no, no.
没事的  放下枪
It's all right. Just stand down.
各位都放下枪  没必要起冲突
Stand down, guys. No bloodshed required.
没事的
It's cool.
让他走
Let him go.
开我的车
Take my car.
长官
Sir?
没关系  让他走
It's okay.
谢谢各位了
Thank you, guys!
没事了
We done?
他走了  就没事了
He's gone. We're done.
逮捕他们
Arrest them.
把你们的枪都放到地上
Put your guns down on the ground...
慢慢地
slowly.
照他说的做
Do as he says.
去追踪里斯本探员的车
Go track Agent Lisbon's vehicle.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
你在我车上装了追踪器
You put a bug on my car?
要不我们怎么能找到简
How do you think we found Jane?
我说过认识你们这些人我很高兴
I said I was glad to see you people
因为我知道你们早晚要出篓子
because I knew you would screw up
能省我不少事
and make my life easy.
你们这不就照做了吗
And you did just that.
谢谢
Thank you.
逮捕她
Arrest her.
走吧
Come on.
他还没准备好呢
He wasn't ready for it.
没错
No.
瞧啊
Check it out.
瞧瞧这个
Check this out.
你好吗
What's up?
能帮我看会儿车吗
Uh, could you guys keep an eye on my car for me, please?
当然了  会看好的
Sure, I'll watch it.
谢谢
Thank you.
动手
Let's go.
好  伙计  别担心
Yeah, man, no worries.
等等
Hey there.
抱歉麻烦你了  女士
Sorry to bother you, ma'am.
说来话长
Uh, long story.
你愿不愿意载我一程
Uh, I need--I need a ride, if you're willing.
这里是四队  我们发现目标车辆了
This is Unit 4. We have the vehicle in sight,
停在第五大道和谢尔曼街交会处
stationary on Fifth and Sherman.
退后  先退后  他们可能就在那儿接头
Stay back, stay back. This could be the meet.
搞什么鬼
What the heck?
四队  什么情况
Unit 4, what's the situation?
四队  回答  该死的
Unit 4, respond, damn it.
头儿  里斯本车里就几个孩子
Boss, it was some kids in Lisbon's car.
简不在里面
Jane wasn't there.
没有发现简  重复  我们没发现简
We don't have Jane. Repeat. We don't have Jane.
是否收...
Do you co--
别再越错越多了
Don't dig yourself any deeper.
他去哪儿了
Where did he go?
不知道
I don't know.
你们是不见棺材不落泪是吧
You guys really have a death wish, don't you?
长官  我们真的不知道
Sir, we really don't know.
长官  你居然还叫他长官
"Sir"? Why the hell are you calling him "Sir"?
别激动  "头号公敌"
Oh, calm down, Dillinger.
约翰.迪林杰是萧条时期联调局追捕的最著名的黑帮头目  曾两度越狱
我们现在是阶下囚  还是识相点吧
We're under arrest here. We might as well be civil.
干嘛  你以为能弄到个好点的牢房
Why? You think you'll get a nicer cell?
非常感谢[西语]  奥雷利奥
Muchas gracias, Aurelio.
别客气  祝你好运[西语]
De nada. Buena suerte.
安琪拉·萝斯金·简
夏洛特·安妮·简
派翠克
Hey, Patrick.
得先得搜搜你身上有没有武器
I'm gonna need to search you for weapons.
然后你才能进去  把手举起来
So you can go ahead, put your hands up.
试下也无妨
Worth a shot.
你可以进去了
You can go in now.
派翠克
Patrick.
谢谢你这么准时
Thank you for being so punctual.
你骗了我
You lied to me.
你不也是
Oh. Well... as did you.
我们还真是俩无赖  对吧
What a couple of scamps we are, huh?
我保证  这是最后一次骗你了
I promise that is the last lie that I will ever tell you.
先说正事
So... first things first.
你和联调局犯了个严重的错误
You and the feds have made a big mistake.
我不是血腥约翰
I'm not Red John.
你说什么
What?
我不是血腥约翰
I'm not Red John.
很抱歉让你失望了
I-I'm sorry to disappoint you,
但是我只是布莱克组织
but I'm just a humble foot soldier
一员卑微走卒罢了
in the Blake Association.
血腥约翰可是高层
Red John is one of the top brass.
我不是很相信你
I'm not sure I believe you.
信不信是你的权利  但
Well... that's your privilege, but--
但是我说的是真的
But I am telling you the truth.
你们的结论都是错的
You all just jumped to the wrong conclusion.
那么谁是血腥约翰
Okay, so who is Red John?
我不知道
Oh, I have no idea.
真的
No, h-honestly.
不知道
No idea.
组织严格遵循的原则是只须知道必需的信息
The association works on a strictly need-to-know basis.
假设你说的是真的
Supposing what you say is true,
那么我们完全可以在电话里说
then we could have had this talk on the phone.
但是如果我们在电话里说
Yeah, but if we talked on the phone,
那你  你可能就不会来见我了
Then you... you probably wouldn't have come to meet me,
不是吗
Would you?
我接到命令要打电话给你
And I was told to call you,
告诉你游戏结束  安排和你见面
tell you the game's over, and arrange a meeting.
为什么
Why?
为什么要我过来
Why am I here?
请你千万不要以为
Please... don't think for a moment
我乐意这么做
that I am happy about this.
组织不想有遗留问题
The association doesn't like loose ends.
他们讨厌留下把柄
Just hates them.
所以
So...
动手吧  奥斯卡
Go on, Oscar.
别  别  听着  听着
No, no. Listen. Listen.
我们谈谈  等等
Let's--let's talk about this. Just... w-wait.
我很抱歉  这不是我能决定的
Now I am truly sorry, but it is totally out of my hands.
我一直都很喜欢你  派翠克
I always liked you, Patrick.
别  别  不需要这么做
No. No. This is not necessary.
我们不
We don't--don't--
什...
H-hey...wh-
谢谢  奥斯卡
Thank you, Oscar.
你可以出去等着了  就...
You can wait outside. Just, uh...
确保没人来打扰我们
Make sure we're left in peace.
你好  派翠克
Hello, Patrick.
你好
Hi.
现在什么情况
Hey, what's going on?
格蕾斯  你在干
Grace, what are you--
你  别这么做
What--please don't do that.
你还不如周呢
You're worse than Cho.
他们必须告诉我们到底怎么了
They need to tell us what's going on.
他们不需要做任何事
They don't need to do anything.
我们也什么都做不了  行行好就放松点吧
And we can't do anything, so please just relax.
放松  我怎么放松得下来
Relax? How can I relax?
你有时候表现的好像你很享受无助感
You know, sometimes I think you like being helpless.
好了  我收回  别放松
Okay, fine, I take it back. Don't relax.
就用额头把车窗撞破
Just break the window with your forehead
我们就可以跳车跑了
and we'll all jump out and make a run for it.
伙计们  团结一点好吗
Guys, let's try to keep it together, okay?
好的  很抱歉
Okay, I'm sorry.
"抱歉"
"Sorry."
莫林斯  你是本地人  对吗
Mullins, you're from here, yes?
是的  长官  林肯高地的
Yes, sir. Over to Lincoln Heights.
-给我弄一张萨克拉门托的地图  -是  长官
- Get me a map of Sacramento. - Yes, sir.
车里的电脑上就有
There's one on the computer in the car.
纸质地图
Paper map.
纸质  地图
Paper... map.
快点去找
Come on. Let's go.
你有纸质地图吗
Hey, do you have a paper map?
派翠克  终于又见面了
Well, Patrick, here we are.
可怜的家伙
Poor fella.
说他聪明他又傻
Smart but dumb.
他从来没想到
It never occurred to him
我也是布莱克组织的一员
that I am the Blake Association.
你为什么要杀他
Why'd you have to kill him?
每个人都认为他是血腥约翰  不是吗
Everyone thinks he's Red John, don't they?
所以你们两个同归于尽
So... it would seem a fitting end to the story
会是这个故事完美的结局
if you two were found dead together.
没人会再深究下去
No one will look any deeper.
所以我也必须死  是吗
So I'm supposed to die, am I?
耗了这么多年
After all these years,
是不是不太公平
seems kind of unfair.
很公平
It's totally fair.
游戏结束  我赢了
The game's over, and I won.
这可不是游戏
It's not a game.
有人输  有人赢  这就是游戏
There's a winner and a loser. That's a game.
我可没要玩这个游戏
It's not a game I asked to play.
即使如此  你还是玩得很好
No, but you played it very well nonetheless.
你很有趣  很有挑战性  谢谢
You were fun, challenging. Thank you.
你肯定有很多问题想问我把
You probably have a lot of questions for me, huh?
我们多得是时间  想问就问吧
We have time, if you want.
我没什么要问的
I have no questions.
你是个邪恶  性变态的反社会人渣
You're an evil, sexually perverted sociopath
还很可悲地妄自尊大
with pathetic delusions of grandeur.
本质如此  其余的只是细节罢了
The rest is just details.
邪恶  性变态的反社会人渣
"Evil, sexually perverted sociopath"?
这一点我到是承认  但是
Well, I guess I have to own that, but, uh...
妄自尊大
"delusions of grandeur"?
我不承认
No.
我从没有妄想
I have no delusions.
我建立了这个地下帝国
I built a secret empire.
我控制着千万人的生命
I control the lives of thousands of people.
我说的话可以决定生死
My word is life and death,
却没有人知道我是谁
and nobody knows who I am.
如果这还不算伟大
Now if that's not grandeur,
那你说算什么
I don't know what you call it.
我会说这是卑鄙的自大狂的胡言乱语
I'd call it the ravings of a squalid egomaniac.
瞧
You see?
你总是这样没来由地粗鲁  目空一切
For no reason at all, you... you're rude and contemptuous.
这就是害死你老婆孩子的原因
That's why your wife and kid are dead.
你又有什么资格
Who are you to butt in here
在这对我评头论足
and make obnoxious judgments about me?
你算什么
Who are you?
你算得上什么
谁也算不上
Nobody.
你以前不了解我
You didn't know me.
现在也不了解我
You don't know me.
你一无所知
You have no idea.
派  你的问题在于
Here's your problem, Pat.
你很聪明  但是太傲慢
You're a smart man, but you are arrogant.
你想不到别人会比你聪明
You can't imagine someone smarter than you.
这就是为什么每一步
Which is why I've been ahead of you
我都能抢在你前面
at every step along the way.
你有枪  想自吹自擂
You're holding the gun. You want to brag?
尽管吹吧  我不会阻止你
Go ahead. I'm not gonna stop you.
你还是不知道我怎么骗过你的  是吗
You still don't know how I fooled you, do you?
我怎么从爆炸中逃脱的
How did I survive that bomb?
我怎么猜出你的名单的
How did I know all the names on your list?
你一直缺少的就是这个对吧  有人能欣赏你
Is this what you've been missing? Appreciation?
想让我为你喝彩吗
Do you want me to applaud?
你一无所知  是吗
You have no idea, do you?
我不知道你是怎么猜到嫌疑人名单的
I don't know how you got the list of suspects.
干得漂亮
That was a good trick.
但是炸弹那事很简单
But the bomb gag is simple.
有两次爆炸
There were two explosions.
第一次是个震央炸弹  为了把所有人炸晕
The first was a concussion bomb, knocked everyone out.
第二个
The second
才是那个炸死哈弗内和斯特尔斯的致命炸弹
lethal bomb that killed Haffner and Stiles
你把我  伯特仑和史密斯
only went off after you dragged Bertram,
拖出爆炸伤害范围之后才引爆的
Smith and me out of harm's way.
没错
Correct.
伪造你的死亡就更简单了
Faking your own death was easy.
布雷特·帕特里奇是布莱克组织的
Brett Partridge was Blake Association.
他可以接触到原始DNA数据库
His job gave him access to the primary D.N.A. database.
他把你的DNA记录
He switched your D.N.A. Records
和你留着的一具尸体的记录对调了
with a body that you had on ice.
一具替代品
A surrogate.
你用把尸体放在汽车后备箱
And you brought the body to my house
带到了我家
in the trunk of your car
然后把尸体放在哈弗内和斯特尔斯旁边
and you put it alongside Stiles and Haffner.
很好
Very good.
好个出色的事后诸葛亮
Your hindsight is 20/20.
能给你看件东西吗
Can I show you something?
当然
Sure.
面包屑
Bread crumbs?
鸟
Birds.
真聪明
Very clever.
炸弹是你犯的一个错误
The bomb was a mistake.
是你演的一出戏
It was theater.
我知道不管事实看起来如何
I knew that whatever the truth looked like,
与之相反的才是真相
The opposite must be true.
求你别
Please don't.
别杀我
Don't kill me.
现在你来祈求宽恕了
Oh, now you want mercy?
在你犯下那么多恶行之后
After all you've done?
你和我不一样
You're not like me.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
杀了我  你会饱受折磨
It'll haunt you.
我可不是在犹豫
Oh, I'm not hesitating.
我只是在享受这一刻
I'm just savoring the moment.
你就是血腥约翰
You're Red John.
我必须承认我有点失望
I have to say I'm a little disappointed.
我的上帝
Oh, my God!
救命啊  他要杀了我
Help! Please! He's gonna kill me!
我的上帝
Oh, my God!
我是警察  请你离开
I'm a policeman, and you need to leave.
先生  很抱歉  你看起来可不像是个警察
Sir, I'm sorry, you don't look like a policeman.
我是警察  照我说的做  立刻离开
Yes, I am. Just do as I say and leave right now.
-请把枪放下  -你必须离开
- Please put down that gun. - You need to go.
不管这是怎么回事
Whatever's happened here,
但是再多的暴力也解决不了问题
more violence is not the answer.
-你不明白  -先生  我当然明白
- No, you don't understand. - Sir, I do understand.
-我知道你很愤怒  -不  你不明白
- I know how angry you must-- - No, you don't,
你必须立刻离开
and you have to go now!
先生  本着良知
Sir, in all good conscience.
他是从这里走的
All right, so he started out here,
在这个小商场弃的车
and he dumped the car here at a mini-mall.
如果是你  会在哪里安排见面
So where would you arrange a meeting?
一个能够出入自由
Someplace with easy access, in and out,
接近高速的地点
close to the highway.
-棒球场  -安保人员太多  这是哪里
- Ballpark. - Too much security. What's that?
社区大学
Community college campus.
不是  是这里
No, that, right there.
那是亚历山大公墓
That's the Alexandria Cemetery.
简的妻子葬在哪里
Where was Jane's wife buried?
-这和那个有什么关系  -她葬在哪里
- What does that have to do-- - Where was she buried?
亚历山大公墓
Alexandria Cemetery.
谢谢
Thanks.
亚历山大公墓  出发
Alexandria Cemetery. Let's go!
我的上帝
Oh, my God.
Oh, no. Oh, my God!
来人啊  救命
Help! Please!
救命啊
Help!
去哪儿了
Which way?
那边
Over there.
B小队  仔细搜索这边
"B" team, canvass this side.
丹耶尔  你跟我来
Denyer, you're with me.
-马上行动  -看他是不是在这
- Let's go now. -Let's see if he's here.
什么动静
What was that?
怎么回事  我在跟警察通话
Oh! What's going on? I'm on the line with the police.
我就是警察  女士  我来跟他们说
I am police, ma'am. Let me talk to them.
谢谢  是这边吗
Thank you. This way?
是
Uh, um, yeah, well...
该死
Ah, hell.
911  请问您有何紧急情况
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
喂
Hello?
911  请问您有何紧急情况
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
求你别杀我  饶我一命吧
Please don't kill me. Let me live.
911  请问您有何紧急情况
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
求你  饶我一命
Please... let me live.
我会告诉你我怎么猜到你的名单的
I'll tell you how I got the names on your list.
我不在乎
I don't care.
我会知道是因为我是真的灵
I-I knew because I have real psychic--
眨一次眼表示不是
I want you to blink once for "no"
两次表示是
and twice for "yes."
你有为你杀了我妻子安琪拉
Are you sorry that you killed my wife Angela
和我女儿夏洛特而感到愧疚吗
and my daughter Charlotte?
很好
Good.
你怕死吗
Are you afraid to die?
很好
Good.
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
里斯本
Lisbon...
结束了
It's over.
都结束了
It's done.
我只是想告诉你我没事
I just want you to know I'm okay.
我会想你的
And I'm gonna miss you.